<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="/blog/tag/random/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2024-05-23T18:58:51+00:00</updated>
  <id>/blog/tag/random/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">Nomad’s Blog | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>You'll find all my tech posts here</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">The Enigma of Genetic Adam and Eve</title>
      <link href="/blog/genetic-adam-eve" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Enigma of Genetic Adam and Eve" />
      <published>2023-04-11T10:18:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2023-04-11T10:18:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/blog/genetic-adam-eve</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/blog/genetic-adam-eve">&lt;p&gt;Understanding Genetic Adam and Eve takes us on a journey through human evolution, diverse genes, and the quest to learn about the origin of humanity. In this article, we will explore the mystery of Genetic Adam and Eve, explaining the science behind these ideas and the interesting insights they provide into our ancient history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Genetic Adam and Eve are not names of real individuals who once walked the Earth. Instead, they are terms used in genetics and anthropology to represent the most recent common ancestors of all modern humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mitochondrial-eve-mtdna&quot;&gt;Mitochondrial Eve (mtDNA)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mitochondrial Eve is the hypothetical common ancestor through the matrilineal line, meaning she is the woman from whom all humans today can trace their mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA). Mitochondria are tiny structures within our cells that carry their own DNA. The unique feature of mtDNA is that it is passed exclusively from mother to offspring, making it an ideal tool for tracing maternal ancestry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mitochondrial Eve is estimated to have lived in Africa around 100,000 to 200,000 years ago. While she wasn’t the only woman alive at her time, her genetic lineage is the only one that has survived to the present day, making her our most recent common maternal ancestor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;y-chromosomal-adam-y-dna&quot;&gt;Y-Chromosomal Adam (Y-DNA)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Y-Chromosomal Adam, on the other hand, represents the most recent common paternal ancestor of all modern humans. The Y-chromosome is passed exclusively from father to son, making it an excellent marker for tracing paternal lineage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like Mitochondrial Eve, Y-Chromosomal Adam wasn’t the only man alive during his time. He also lived in Africa around 100,000 to 200,000 years ago. His Y-chromosome lineage is the only one to have persisted through the generations, making him the common paternal ancestor for all males in our species.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Inheritance of Y-DNA and mt-DNA between generations&quot; src=&quot;assets/images/dnainheritance.png&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Inheritance of Y-DNA and mt-DNA between generations&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-out-of-africa-theory&quot;&gt;The “Out of Africa” Theory&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the “Out of Africa” theory, our species, Homo sapiens, emerged in Africa approximately 200,000 years ago. This emergence is marked by a key event in our evolutionary history known as anatomically modern Homo sapiens. These early modern humans possessed the physical traits and cognitive abilities that are characteristic of modern humans today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From their African homeland, these early Homo sapiens began to disperse and migrate to other continents. The migration out of Africa is believed to have occurred in multiple waves, with the first significant exodus happening around 70,000 to 100,000 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most compelling pieces of evidence supporting this theory is the genetic diversity seen in human populations around the world. As humans migrated to different regions, they adapted to their new environments, resulting in the development of distinct physical traits and genetic markers in different populations. However, despite these regional adaptations, all humans share a common genetic heritage that can be traced back to their African ancestors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The presence of Genetic Adam and Eve in Africa aligns with the “Out of Africa” theory. Both Mitochondrial Eve and Y-Chromosomal Adam are estimated to have lived on the African continent during the same time period when early modern humans were spreading across the continent and eventually beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/nature.2013.13478&quot;&gt;Genetic Adam and Eve did not live too far apart in time&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://med.stanford.edu/news/all-news/2013/08/common-genetic-ancestors-lived-during-roughly-same-time-period-scientists-find.html&quot;&gt;Common genetic ancestors lived during roughly same time period, scientists find&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Lahiru Udayanga</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="random" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Understanding Genetic Adam and Eve takes us on a journey through human evolution, diverse genes, and the quest to learn about the origin of humanity. In this article, we will explore the mystery of Genetic Adam and Eve, explaining the science behind these ideas and the interesting insights they provide into our ancient history.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Down The Rabbit Hole</title>
      <link href="/blog/down-the-rabbit-hole" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Down The Rabbit Hole" />
      <published>2023-04-11T10:18:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2023-04-11T10:18:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/blog/down-the-rabbit-hole</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/blog/down-the-rabbit-hole">&lt;p&gt;The grandfather paradox is a famous thought experiment that explores the consequences of time travel. The paradox poses the question: “If you could go back in time and kill your grandfather before he had children, would you still exist?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The paradox arises from the idea that if you prevented your grandfather from having children, then you would never have been born to go back in time to kill him. This creates a logical contradiction, as your existence both depends on and contradicts the premise of time travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Siwa city&quot; src=&quot;assets/images/grandfather-paradox-and-time-travel.png&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Diagram that shows the paradox&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The grandfather paradox is often used to illustrate the complexities and potential pitfalls of time travel. It suggests that any attempt to change the past could result in unpredictable and potentially disastrous consequences for the present and future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the paradox has also led to many interesting and creative interpretations and solutions. Some scientists and philosophers have proposed that time travel could be possible if it exists in a parallel universe or if the act of traveling through time creates a new timeline that diverges from the original.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Others have argued that the paradox itself may be flawed, as it assumes a linear and deterministic view of time that may not reflect the true nature of the universe. The paradox raises many intriguing questions about the nature of time and the possibilities and limitations of human understanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, the grandfather paradox is a fascinating thought experiment that challenges our assumptions and beliefs about time and causality. While it may never be possible to travel back in time and test the paradox, it continues to inspire and intrigue scientists, philosophers, and writers alike.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Lahiru Udayanga</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="random" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">The grandfather paradox is a famous thought experiment that explores the consequences of time travel. The paradox poses the question: “If you could go back in time and kill your grandfather before he had children, would you still exist?”</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">When life gives you limes and mint, make a Bacardi Mojito 🍃🍈</title>
      <link href="/blog/when-life-gives-you-limes-and-mint-make-a-bacardi-mojito" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="When life gives you limes and mint, make a Bacardi Mojito 🍃🍈" />
      <published>2023-04-11T01:18:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2023-04-11T01:18:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/blog/when-life-gives-you-limes-and-mint-make-a-bacardi-mojito</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/blog/when-life-gives-you-limes-and-mint-make-a-bacardi-mojito">&lt;p&gt;Are you in the mood for a refreshing and tangy cocktail? Look no further than the Bacardi Mojito! This classic Cuban cocktail is a perfect summer drink, combining the fresh flavors of lime and mint with a smooth Bacardi rum kick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make a Bacardi Mojito, you will need:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;50 ml Bacardi rum&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;25 ml freshly squeezed lime juice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;25 ml simple syrup (equal parts sugar and water dissolved together)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5-8 fresh mint leaves&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Club soda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instructions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Put fresh mint leaves, simple syrup, and lime juice in a glass. Use a spoon or fork to press down on the mint leaves to release their flavor. 🍃🍬🍈&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add ice cubes to the glass and pour in 2 ounces of Bacardi rum. Mix everything together. 🧊🥃&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add a little club soda to the glass and stir gently. 🥤&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add more club soda until the glass is full. Stir again. 🌊🥤&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finally, add a sprig of mint and a slice of lime to the glass. Enjoy your Bacardi Mojito! 🌿🍋&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Delft Island Fort&quot; src=&quot;assets/images/barcadi-diy.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;DIY Barcadi Mojito in 10 mins&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Lahiru Udayanga</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="random" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Are you in the mood for a refreshing and tangy cocktail? Look no further than the Bacardi Mojito! This classic Cuban cocktail is a perfect summer drink, combining the fresh flavors of lime and mint with a smooth Bacardi rum kick.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
