<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="/blog/tag/travel/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2024-05-23T18:58:51+00:00</updated>
  <id>/blog/tag/travel/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">Nomad’s Blog | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>You'll find all my tech posts here</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">From Sunset to Sunrise….</title>
      <link href="/blog/from-sunset-to-sunrise" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="From Sunset to Sunrise...." />
      <published>2024-05-23T10:18:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2024-05-23T10:18:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/blog/from-sunset-to-sunrise</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/blog/from-sunset-to-sunrise">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://maps.app.goo.gl/2gpcmkuo7f1uL7V89&quot;&gt;Blue beach island&lt;/a&gt; is a small island located in the Nilwella area in between Dickwella and Tangalle. The island is known for its stunning sunsets and tranquil environment, making it an ideal spot to escape the hustle and bustle of everyday life. The island is connected to the mainland by a small narrow sand dune which can be submerged by sea water during high tides or during the southwest monsoons. For this reason, it is advisable to plan your visit in advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reserve-a-spot-for-night-camping-️&quot;&gt;Reserve a spot for night camping 🏕️&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blue beach island is a private property and the owners only allow a limited number of people for a night stay at the island. So you have to contact the owner and reserve a spot in advance. It is advisable to put your reservation before few weeks if you are planning to stay during a weekend. We paid 1000 LKR per head for the camping and we additionally rented the camping gear from the owner for an additional 800 LKR for a 4 person tent. The owner also offered for a BBQ on the beach for 500 LKR per head but we refused as we wanted to do it by ourselves with a bonfire. You can contact the owner via one of the following channels and reserve a spot for night camping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;📧 bluebeachislandsl@gmail.com&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;☎️ 077 810 2557&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ⓕ &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/beachcampingsrilanka/&quot;&gt;Blue Beach Island&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-there-&quot;&gt;Getting there 🚗&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are travelling from Colombo, you can take the southern highway and exit from the Aparekka interchange and from there take the route shown in the google maps to reach the blue beach island. Closest city is Dickwella and you can buy food, alcohol and all your required stuff from the Dickwella city. Also if you are taking the train, you can get off from the station Wewrukannala depending on the train you choose. From there you have to take a taxi to reach the blue beach island.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First you have to go to the owner’s home which is like 1 km from the beach and park your vehicle there. There are like 3 parking spots and it’s allocated on a first come first serve basis. Otherwise you’ll have to park your vehicle outside in the streets which is not recommended due to the security concerns. They ask you to be there around 4 - 5 pm for the introduction session that explains all the required stuff for night camping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;once-you-get-there-&quot;&gt;Once you get there 🤩&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you arrive at Blue Beach Island, you will be absolutely stunned by the beauty of its surrounding and the unique sand dune with sea waves gently lapping on both sides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Blue beach island&quot; src=&quot;assets/images/blue-beach-sand.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sand dune that connects the island to the mainland&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to go through the sand dune, climb a small hill and then reach the tiny hidden beach reserved for camping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-familiar-with-the-island-&quot;&gt;Getting familiar with the island 🧭&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To reach the camping site follow the red arrows.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To reach the view point from the camping site, there’s a small walking trail through the bushes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Blue beach island&quot; src=&quot;assets/images/blue-beach-camping.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Blue beach island, Nilwella&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Blue beach island&quot; src=&quot;assets/images/blue-beach-camping-site.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Camping site&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Blue beach island&quot; src=&quot;assets/images/blue-beach-sea-urchin.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Me holding a sea urchin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;let-the-night-begin-&quot;&gt;Let the night begin 🔥&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After exploring the island and watching the glamorous sunset, we started to prepare the bonfire and the BBQ. We bought some woods on the way to the island near the Nilwella fishing harbour. Several houses nearby also sell chopped wood for bonfires. We had some beers while the chicken and sausages get marinated for the BBQ. We spent the full night drinking, singing and dancing untill around 3 am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Blue beach island&quot; src=&quot;assets/images/blue-beach-bonfire.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Bonfire and BBQ&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Blue beach island&quot; src=&quot;assets/images/blue-beach-bbq.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Chicken BBQ with my favorite beer&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wrapping-up-️&quot;&gt;Wrapping up ☑️&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We didn’t actually sleep as it was raining heavily after 3 am and not that much comfy for a sleep inside the tent. We woke up around 5.30 am to watch the sunrise and prepared some sandwiches for the breakfast. We left the camping site around 8.30 am and we spent some time in the water near the sand dune as the waves were not that strong during those days. It is advisable to seek some guidance from a local villager before jumping in the water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Blue beach island&quot; src=&quot;assets/images/blue-beach-final.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;A distant drone shot of the blue beach island. Nilwella fishing harbour is visible in the corner&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Lahiru Udayanga</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="travel" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Blue beach island is a small island located in the Nilwella area in between Dickwella and Tangalle. The island is known for its stunning sunsets and tranquil environment, making it an ideal spot to escape the hustle and bustle of everyday life. The island is connected to the mainland by a small narrow sand dune which can be submerged by sea water during high tides or during the southwest monsoons. For this reason, it is advisable to plan your visit in advance.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Siwa, The Hidden Gem of Egypt’s Western Desert</title>
      <link href="/blog/siwa-the-hidden-gem-of-egypts-western-desert" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Siwa, The Hidden Gem of Egypt's Western Desert" />
      <published>2023-04-11T10:18:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2023-04-11T10:18:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/blog/siwa-the-hidden-gem-of-egypts-western-desert</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/blog/siwa-the-hidden-gem-of-egypts-western-desert">&lt;p&gt;It’s amazing how a single photo can travel you back to a place you visited years ago. Today, I find myself reminiscing about my time in Siwa, Egypt which I visited back in July 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Siwa is an ancient city located in Egypt’s western desert near the border with Libya, known for its natural beauty and unique &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newworldencyclopedia.org/entry/Berber&quot;&gt;Berber culture&lt;/a&gt;. The city is situated on an oasis, surrounded by palm groves, freshwater springs, and a salt lake that glimmers in the desert sun. Siwa is also home to several ancient temples, including the &lt;a href=&quot;https://sacredsites.com/africa/egypt/temple_of_amun_siwa_oasis.html&quot;&gt;Temple of the Oracle of Amun&lt;/a&gt;, which dates back to the 6th century BCE and was a site of pilgrimage for ancient Egyptians seeking divine guidance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was fortunate enough to explore Siwa, Egypt as part of a 6-week volunteering program organized by AIESEC. This opportunity not only allowed me to give back to the community but also gave me the chance to immerse myself in the unique culture and natural beauty of this hidden gem in the heart of the Sahara desert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started the journey from Cairo on July 28, 2018, and first we went to Alexandria. From Alexandria, we went to Marsa Matruh and took the Marsa Matruh - Siwa road, which took around 12 hours to reach Siwa. We checked in to a nice, cozy garden hotel in the center of Siwa, which I don’t remember the name exactly. After relaxing for a few hours, we explored Siwa City, which is basically a classical Middle Eastern bazaar with some hotels and restaurants that are targeted at tourists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Siwa city&quot; src=&quot;assets/images/siwa-city.png&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Siwa City Center&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Temple of the Oracle of Amun is a must-visit destination for anyone interested in ancient Egyptian history and mythology. It was constructed during the reign of the pharaoh Nectanebo II in the fourth century BCE and was dedicated to the god Amun, who was worshipped throughout ancient Egypt as the king of the gods. The temple complex includes a main temple, several smaller temples, and a series of underground chambers that were used for religious ceremonies and burials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the temple and a quick tour around the city center, we headed to a natural water spring named Cleopatra’s Spring / Bath. It is said to be the spot where the legendary queen Cleopatra once bathed, and it has been a popular destination for tourists for many years. Pretty cool right ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Cleopatra's Spring&quot; src=&quot;assets/images/cleopatras.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Cleopatra's Spring&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After spending few hours at Cleopatra’s Spring, we headed back to the hotel and then started getting ready for the most amazing part of the day; sleeping under the stars in the desert !!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We packed our bags with snacks, beer and water and headed for the desert camp. On the way we stopped at this lake hidden in the desert named Siwa Cold Lake. As the name implies the water in the lake was sooo freaking cold !!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After spending around 1 hour at the Cold lake, we headed back for the final destination of the day; the desert camp that we are going to spend the night. There was no proper road to the desert camp and so we had to go through a bumpy V8 ride in the desert with some crazyyy stunts by our driver Ali.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Bumpy V8 ride through sand dunes&quot; src=&quot;assets/images/jeeps.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Bumpy V8 ride through sand dunes&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some photos I captured on the way to the desert camp are listed below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Taking a selfie&quot; src=&quot;assets/images/siwa-selfie.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Taking a selfie&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Driving through the sand dunes&quot; src=&quot;assets/images/siwa-driver.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Driving through the sand dunes&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Cold Lake&quot; src=&quot;assets/images/siwa-cold.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Cold Lake&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent several hours in the desert sand boarding, watching sunset and taking photos. Here’s a glimpse of me holding the Sri Lankan flag in the Sahara Desert, possibly making me the first person to hold the Sri Lankan flag in this desert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Siwa Sri Lankan flag&quot; src=&quot;assets/images/siwa-srilanka.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Me holding the Sri Lankan flag&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we settled ourselves in the desert camp, partied all night, drinking beers and singing beside a bonfire, and slept in the desert under open skies, watching the stars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Desert camp&quot; src=&quot;assets/images/siwa-night.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Desert camp&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Lahiru Udayanga</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="travel" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">It’s amazing how a single photo can travel you back to a place you visited years ago. Today, I find myself reminiscing about my time in Siwa, Egypt which I visited back in July 2018.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Off the Beaten Path, Finding Serenity on Delft Island</title>
      <link href="/blog/off-the-beaten-path-finding-serenity-on-delft-island" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Off the Beaten Path, Finding Serenity on Delft Island" />
      <published>2023-04-11T10:18:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2023-04-11T10:18:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/blog/off-the-beaten-path-finding-serenity-on-delft-island</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/blog/off-the-beaten-path-finding-serenity-on-delft-island">&lt;p&gt;Jaffna, located in the northern part of Sri Lanka, is known for its rich cultural heritage, stunning coastline, and natural beauty. Among the many hidden gems in Jaffna is the enchanting Delft Island, located off the coast of the Jaffna Peninsula. Delft Island, also known as Neduntheevu, is a small island surrounded by crystal-clear turquoise waters and dotted with palm trees, pristine beaches, and unique wildlife. The island’s name is derived from the city of Delft in the Netherlands, reflecting the Dutch colonial influence on the island’s history. This island has a fascinating past, dating back to the Chola Dynasty and the Dutch colonial period, and is home to ancient ruins and landmarks that are worth exploring. In this travel blog, I’ll take you on a journey through Delft Island in Jaffna, sharing my experiences and recommendations for the best things to see, do, and eat on this enchanting island. So, get ready to discover the natural beauty, cultural richness, and unique wildlife of Delft Island in Jaffna.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To reach Delft Island from the mainland, there’s a public ferry service run by the Sri Lankan Navy that operates three times a day. We decided to take the morning ferry from Kurikadduwan Jetty, which departs at around 8 am. This morning ferry service can be quite crowded, as it’s primarily used by government workers who commute to the pradeshiya sabha, police station, and school on the island and are given priority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Ferry service&quot; src=&quot;assets/images/delft-ferry.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Vessels that are used by the Sri Lankan Navy to operate the ferry service&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you arrive at the Delft Island jetty, the Sri Lankan Navy will ask for an identity verification, and you have to present a valid National Identity Card or a valid passport. They may also ask about the purpose of the visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although walking is a possible way to explore the island, it is strongly recommended that you rent a vehicle for a tour because walking in the scorching heat can be quite difficult. We decided to rent a cab that was specially designed for sightseeing and managed to cover all the major attractions in just one day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dutch hospital and the English Court&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hospital was built by the Dutch during their colonial rule in Sri Lanka and was used to treat the wounded soldiers of the Dutch East India Company. Later, the building was used as an administrative court complex by the British. There is an inscription in the door that indicates the year in which this court was established, that is, 1905, and the initials of the then-ruling King Edward VII. Along with the court, they had a prison to keep the prisoners until the court proceedings took place, an advocates chamber, and also a room for the judge. The building has now been renovated by the Archeological Department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another remarkable structure among the ruins is the Pigeon Cote. This building was used to house messenger pigeons used for communication during the time of the Dutch. There are around seventy pigeonholes on the building. Interestingly, the structure has mostly remained intact until today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Pigeon Cote&quot; src=&quot;assets/images/delft-pigeon.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Pigeon Cote&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Baobab Tree brought from Africa&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The baobab tree, also known as Adansonia digitata, is native to East Africa and was introduced to Sri Lanka by Arabian traders in the 7th century. This particular baobab tree is believed to be over 800 years old, making it one of the largest and oldest baobab trees in Sri Lanka. According to some sources, the tree was brought to Sri Lanka by African laborers who were brought to the island by the Dutch to work on plantations. Others claim that the Arab traders brought the tree over in 700 A.D. during the Portuguese rule. Regardless of its origins, the Baobab tree on Delft Island remains a remarkable natural wonder and a popular attraction for visitors to Sri Lanka.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Baobab Tree&quot; src=&quot;assets/images/delft-baobab.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Baobab Tree&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The great banyan tree&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Banyan tree in Delft Island is located near the Baobab tree and is estimated to be over 200 years old. It has a circumference of approximately 400 feet, making it one of the largest banyan trees in Sri Lanka. The tree’s aerial roots form a network of trunks and branches that have created a natural canopy, providing shade for visitors who come to see the tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The banyan tree is considered a sacred tree by the locals, and many believe that it has healing powers. The tree is an important part of the local culture and a popular spot for visitors to take photos and explore the intricate root system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;The great banyan tree&quot; src=&quot;assets/images/delft-banyan.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The great banyan tree&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Growing Stone&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like the growing stone in Nagapooshani Amman kovil, there is another lesser-known growing stone in Delft Island. The history behind this stone is lost in time, but the elderly locals who have lived on the island their whole life claim that they have seen this stone grow over the years. The locals worship this stone, and it’s considered a small shrine where lamps are lit and offerings are made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Growing Stone&quot; src=&quot;assets/images/delft-growing.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Growing Stone&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Giant Footprint&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A giant one metre long foot print on Limestone which locals believe is the imprint of Hindu god Hanuman’s right foot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;The Giant Footprint&quot; src=&quot;assets/images/delft-giant.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The Giant Footprint&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Queen’s Tower&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Queen’s Tower is a tower built by the Dutch during their rule in the country. Located on South East cost of Delft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Used as a lighthouse or a navigation point by both the Dutch and the British. Fire was set at the base of the tower, and depending on the time of day, either smoke or fire was sent up the chimney.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Queen’s Tower&quot; src=&quot;assets/images/delft-queen.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Queen’s Tower&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Delft Island Fort&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fort was built by the Portuguese in the 16th century and later occupied by the Dutch in the 17th century. It is an interesting example of Portuguese military architecture in Sri Lanka and features a combination of European and local design elements. The fort was a two-story building constructed entirely out of coral and limestone. It was originally built as a small fortification to protect the island’s salt pans, which were an important source of revenue for the Portuguese.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, the Dutch expanded and strengthened the fort, adding several buildings, including a large warehouse, the commander’s residence, and a church. Today, the fort is in ruins, but some of its walls and buildings are still standing and can be visited by tourists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Delft Island Fort&quot; src=&quot;assets/images/delft-fort.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Delft Island Fort&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to these, there are a number of ancient churches, ruins of Buddhist stupas dating back to the Cholan era, and lots of wild horses that roam freely on the island. Attached below are some photos captured on the island, each accompanied by a brief description.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Delft Island Fort&quot; src=&quot;assets/images/delft-fishing.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;A small fishing village by the edge of the island&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Delft Island Fort&quot; src=&quot;assets/images/delft-beach.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sunset as seen from Delft Mavalithurai Beach&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Delft Island Fort&quot; src=&quot;assets/images/delft-palmyrah.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Palmyrah toddy&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Delft Island Fort&quot; src=&quot;assets/images/delft-beba.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Me with Supun AKA &quot;Beba&quot; :-D&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For anyone looking for tips and recommendations about visiting Delft Island,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are only three ferries per day. If you are planning to do a one-day tour, take the morning ferry and hire a tuk tuk or a cab to explore the island. Be back at the jetty on time for the ferry back to the mainland.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you are planning on staying overnight on the island, make a hotel reservation prior. Only one hotel is on the island, and you have to book it in advance. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tripadvisor.com/Hotel_Review-g304135-d12862271-Reviews-Delft_Samudra_Hotel-Jaffna_Northern_Province.html&quot;&gt;Delft Samudra Hotel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are no ATM machines on the island, so take the required amount of cash with you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take some snacks, chocolates, and water bottles with you as there is only one shop on the island with very limited items.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For anyone looking for a guide, please contact &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/anistan.vinu&quot;&gt;Anistan&lt;/a&gt; via Facebook. We hired him, and he’s a trustworthy, pretty cool guy. (This is not any kind of paid promotion. Just my honest recommendation for anyone looking for a guide.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finally, for anyone who’s looking forward to getting wasted with Palmyrah Toddy, please contact Anistan, and he even accepts the payment with toddy ;-D&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Lahiru Udayanga</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="travel" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Jaffna, located in the northern part of Sri Lanka, is known for its rich cultural heritage, stunning coastline, and natural beauty. Among the many hidden gems in Jaffna is the enchanting Delft Island, located off the coast of the Jaffna Peninsula. Delft Island, also known as Neduntheevu, is a small island surrounded by crystal-clear turquoise waters and dotted with palm trees, pristine beaches, and unique wildlife. The island’s name is derived from the city of Delft in the Netherlands, reflecting the Dutch colonial influence on the island’s history. This island has a fascinating past, dating back to the Chola Dynasty and the Dutch colonial period, and is home to ancient ruins and landmarks that are worth exploring. In this travel blog, I’ll take you on a journey through Delft Island in Jaffna, sharing my experiences and recommendations for the best things to see, do, and eat on this enchanting island. So, get ready to discover the natural beauty, cultural richness, and unique wildlife of Delft Island in Jaffna.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
